JACOB ALSPAW

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Versatile and motivated software engineer with 7 years of experience in industry as a full-stack developer. Seeking position that will use my engineering / design skills to add significant creativity, talent, and professional service to company ventures.

(636) 699-7344

Littleton, Colorado 🗣

jacob-alspaw.com 1

linkedin.com/in/jacob-alspaw in

EXPERIENCE

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER & SATELLITE OPERATOR, LOFT ORBITAL

- Works with a diverse and talented team of Engineers in Europe and the United States to help build the next missions and apps to test and pilot spacecraft
- Demonstrates in-depth knowledge of core web/browser concepts, and other web development/testing/production tools using Vue.js (2&3), TypeScript, GraphQL, Apollo Client, Webpack, and Vite
- Introduced new patterns for backlog management, Jira ticket templating, Gitlab merge request templating, code linting, and code formatting to increase developer productivity
- Pilots and controls satellites in orbit after completing satellite pilot training and certification
- Routinely engages in satellite operations to ensure satellites remain performant

MAY 2019 - JANUARY 2022

FRONT-END LEAD & FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER, IBM URBANCODE, HCL SOFTWARE

- Manages the efforts of the front-end development team responsible for producing, maintaining, and modifying web front-end code for two major DevOps software product offerings through IBM and HCL Software
- Ensures that correct content, product assortments, and UI functionality is developed, tested, scheduled, and validated against business expectations before it is released to clients
- Solves complex design problems to maximize user experience through collaboration with design teams
- Identified and fixed various performance traps that resulted in web pages rendering up to 125x faster
- Reduced known UI defects in product backlog by over 90% in less than 10 months to improve client relations
- Received the highest form of accreditation, distinguished, during all performance reviews

MAY 2019 - JANUARY 2022

CLIENT ADVOCATE & L3 SUPPORT, IBM URBANCODE

- Collaborated as part of an international support team with IBM engineers to maintain company relations and meet SLA on issues that impact millions of dollars in financial investments
- Maintained personal relationships with high-profile customer accounts that need a dedicated advocate for their issues
- Identified a variety of issues that customers faced such as Java JRE bugs, network connectivity issues, licensing issues, product defects, and more
- Helped customers devise and enact plans for upgrading our product across multiple testing environments to ensure integrity of upgrade processes and customer data

MAY 2016 - AUGUST 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN, POINTE BLANK SOLUTIONS

- Developed an enterprise suite of web applications that streamlines the justice process and integrates law enforcement agencies, prosecutors, courts and defense attorneys in fifty plus counties across Ohio
- Routinely performed full-stack feature development and system maintenance using C#, SQL Server databases, .NET, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Typescript, jQuery, both server-side and client-side rendering systems, code ownership paradigms, automated deployment systems, version control systems such as Git, and mass integration / unit testing

AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2019

PROJECT FOUNDER & LEAD ENGINEER, CWRUded

- Designed and developed a data-driven web service (NodeJS, MongoDB, React), and iOS mobile application with senior university faculty that computed and conveyed real-time "busyness" metrics for various locations around campus
- Solution leveraged address resolution protocol (ARP) and Cisco Prime Infrastructure API that manages CWRU wireless network to expose and aggregate unique active clients connected to wireless access points throughout campus
- Planned and lead meetings with campus deans, network admins, and IT marketing team to bring service to students

APRIL 2015 – FEBUARY 2016

PROJECT MANAGER & LEAD DEVELOPER, LYGENT

- Served as project manager and lead developer of a novel vision screening tool (iStrab™) intended for the measurement of strabismus in children, a treatable disorder in which the eyes become misaligned
- Awarded \$25,000 grant from the Innovation Fund to continue development of the iStrab™ diagnostic equipment
- Project is closely associated with University Hospital's eye clinic and CWRU, and was pending FDA clearance in 2016

AUGUST 2018 - DECEMBER 2018

PROJECT MANAGER & FRONT-END LEAD, SYNCHRONY (CAPSTONE PROJECT)

- Developed a synchronized streaming service that enhances user experience through shared playlist collaboration and discovery. Spotify implemented the same features roughly a year after our project was acknowledged and published
- Awarded academic honors in Spring of 2019 for the year's most outstanding capstone project in electrical engineering and computer science departments

AUGUST 2016 - MAY 2019

TEACHING ASSISTANT & PEER TUTOR, CASE WESTERN RESERVE UNIVERSITY

- Reinforced course work during tutoring sessions and recitations to boost students' academic performance
- Customized instructional approaches to meet the academic needs of diverse clients across a variety of courses
- Collaborated with faculty members to ensure lesson plans addressed students' strengths/weaknesses
- Graded student assignments, quizzes, and tests. Kept scores updated in university database

EDUCATION

MAY 2019

B.S. in COMPUTER SCIENCE, CASE WESTERN RESERVE UNIVERSITY

- Degree Path: B.S. in Computer Science with a focus in Software Engineering
- Major GPA: 3.634 / 4.0
- Relevant coursework: object-oriented programming, systems programming, algorithms, databases, systems security
 and networks, discrete mathematics, data structures, software design techniques and craftmanship, mobile
 application development, programming language concepts, team organization and project management

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, C#, Swift, C++, SQL, NoSQL, HTML, CSS, React, Vue, Angular, GraphQL, Apollo, MATLAB, Node, .NET, Webpack, Vite, Git, Yarn, npm, Photoshop, Jira, Jenkins, SalesForce, Agile, Scrum, DevOps, CI/CD, TDD

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Strong work ethic
- Dependable
- Positive attitude
- Team oriented
- Self-motivated
- Flexible
- Forward thinker
- Effective communicator